Ian Dexter D. Marquez

Linux systems administrator

+31 6 1197 1691 im@iandexter.net https://www.iandexter.net

With more than 15 years extensive experience in administering Linux and Unix platforms. Develops and maintains various automation tools for infrastructure management and application deployment. Collaborates with global software development and operations teams in application delivery and support. Certified in Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Microsoft Windows, and ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management.

Qualifications

Bachelor of Science in Computing major in Computer Science, 2011

Technological University of the Philippines, Manila

Red Hat Certified Engineer, October 2008 (NOT CURRENT)

ITIL v₃ Foundation in IT Service Management, JULY 2008

Red Hat Certified Technician, November 2006

Microsoft Certified Professional, May 2006

Trend Micro Certified Security Expert, June 2006

Interests

DevOps, Cloud infrastructure, PaaS, IaaS

Skill areas

- Unix/Linux systems administration (18 years / advanced)
- Infrastructure automation (10 years / proficient)
- Application deployment and support (13 years / advanced)
- Network design, development and administration (5 years / proficient)
- Web design, development and management (3 years / proficient)
- Identity management (2 years / proficient)

Languages

- Bash (18 years / advanced)
- Perl (9 years / proficient)
- PHP (3 years / proficient)
- Python (8 years / proficient)
- SQL (2 years / proficient)
- JavaScript (7 years / proficient)

Platforms

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Fedora (18 years / advanced)
- SuSE Linux Enterprise Server (4 years / advanced)
- Ubuntu, Debian (8 years / proficient)
- Sun Solaris, IBM AIX (1 year / basic)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (1 year / basic)

EXPERIENCE

Platform technical solutions engineer

FEBRUARY 2020 TO PRESENT

Databricks

Provides technical guidance and advice to customers in their Databricks journey. Databricks helps data teams solve the world's toughest problems by providing a unified data analytics platform for massive scale data engineering and collaborative data science.

Support and deployment engineer

FEBRUARY 2019 TO JANUARY 2020

Bright Computing

Supported customers in managing their high-performance clusters (HPC) using Bright Cluster Manager (BCM). Bright Computing develops high-quality software for deploying and managing high-performance clusters, Kubernetes clusters, and OpenStack private clouds in on-premise data centers and public cloud platforms.

Senior DevOps engineer

DECEMBER 2015 TO DECEMBER 2018

Compare Global Group

Headed the distributed team that handles the maintenance and operation of the organization's cloud infrastructure. CompareGlobalGroup is the most comprehensive financial comparison platform in the world, with presence in Asia, Europe and Latin America.

DevOps engineer (part-time)

NOVEMBER 2014 TO NOVEMBER 2015

Compare Global Group

Linux system administrator

APRIL 2010 TO DECEMBER 2015

Asian Development Bank (under RCG IT, Inc.)

Developed and maintained automation tools to manage the Unix infrastructure for the Bank's mission-critical applications like ERP, data warehousing, financials, and business intelligence. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

Senior software engineer

MAY 2007 TO APRIL 2010

Accenture, Inc.

Unix system administrator

JANUARY 2007 TO APRIL 2007

Asian Development Bank (under Cytronics, Inc.)

Systems engineer

April 2006 to January 2007

Trend Micro, Inc.

Linux and web administrator

July 2004 to March 2006

Philippine Rice Research Institute

Network administrator

APRIL 2002 TO JULY 2004

National Irrigation Administration

${\bf Community\ relations\ /\ information\ assistant}$

FEBRUARY 1999 TO MARCH

2002

National Irrigation Administration

Last update: 15 February 2020